Candice F. Ransom Papers
© 2011 University of Connecticut
Candice F. Ransom Papers.
undated, 1981-2001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Ransom, Candice F., 1952-
6.5 1inear feet.
A children's book author since 1980, Ms. Ransom has donated original manuscripts, notes, proofs, galleys, and books. She has also donated original manuscripts from twenty-five novels (including reference and research materials) and thirty other published works (including some foreign language editions).
MSS19940013
Biography
Candace F. Ransom was born in Washington, D.C. and is the author of over twenty-five children's books.
Scope and Content
The collection contains original manuscripts, notes, proofs, galleys, and books.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged as received in chronological order by subject within each box.
Series I: Inventory ( undated, 1981-2001 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Ransom, Candice F., 1952-.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.; Publications.; Artwork.; Illustrations.; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.; Typescripts.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Sketches.; Drawings.
Restrictions on Access
Researchers must make arrangements with the curator to access this collection.
Acquisition Information
Ms. Ransom began donating her materials in July 1999.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1981-2001
  - Subject files 1-10, undated, 1985 (Box 1)
    Includes: Manuscripts, clippings, notes.
  - Subject files 11-17, undated, 1981 (Box 2)
    Includes: Notes, photographs, clippings, publications, manuscripts, books, postcards, correspondence, maps.
  - Subject files 18-32, undated, 1986 (Box 3)
    Includes: Manuscripts.
  - Books, 1986-1992 (Box 4)
    Languages of books: English, French, Indonesian, Spanish, Swedish, German, and Norwegian.
  - Book materials, undated, 1986-1997 (Box 5)
    All Boxcar Children Series published by Albert Whitman and Scholastic under the name of Gertrude Chandler Warner.
    - Boxcar Children Series Special #12 The Black Raven Mystery
      [Retitled, 1999. Original mss.]
    - Boxcar Children Series #66 The Panther Mystery, undated
      [Retitled, 1998. Original mss.]
    - Boxcar Children Series #63 The Mystery at Peacock Hiall, undated
      [Retitled, 1998. Original mss, notes and research.]
    - Boxcar Children Series #59 The Outer Space Mystery, 1997
      [original mss, final mss.]
    - Boxcar Children Series #55 The Mystery of the Secret Message, 1996
      [Original mss.]
    - Boxcar Children Series #52 The Mystery of the Lost Mind, 1996
    - Between Two Worlds (Scholastic), 1994
      [Edited mss.]
    - More than a Name (Macmillan), 1995
      [Original mss (Chapter 1 missing), notes.]
    - Teacher's pest (Troll), 1996
      [Final mss, copy of book, jacket flat.]
    - Jimmy Crack Corn (Carolrhoda), 1994
      [Final mss, notes, research.]
    - Fire in the Sky (Carolrhoda), 1997
      [First proof, final mss, notes, research.]
    - When the Whippoorwill Calls (Tambourine), 1995
      [Edited mss, galleys, notes, f&g.]
    - One Christmas Dawn (Bridgewater), 1996
      [Final mss, sketches, catalog.]
    - The Christmas Dolls (Walker), 1998
      [Retitled. Final mss, sketches, color proofs.]
    - Mother Teresa (On my own biography, Carolrhoda Books), 2001
      [Black and white first pass proofs, sketches by illustrator Elaine Verstraete, final edited draft, drafts (including revision notes), letter from editor, research note cards.]
    - Boxcar Children Series Special#17 The Mystery of the Tiger's Eye (Albert Whitman, 2001
      [Mss with editor's comments, editor's notes, working synopsis, synopsis.]
    - Boxcar Children Series Special #16 The Mystery of the Screech Owl (Albert Whitman), 2001
      [Mss, editor's notes, outline, research notes.]
    - Boxcar Children Series #77 The Mystery of the Wild Ponies (Albert Whitman), 2000
      [Mss, outline, notes, revision notes from editors.]
    - Boxcar Children Series Special #14 The Homerun Mystery (Albert Whitman), 2000
      [Mss, outline, editor's revision notes.]
    - Boxcar Children Series #71 The Ghost Town Mystery (Albert Whitman), 1999
    - Boxcar Children Series #73 The Gymnastics Mystery (Albert Whitman), 1999
      [Mss, draft mss, outline, notes.]
    - Adventures of Benny and Watch #5 Watch Runs Away (Albert Whitman), 1999
      [Mss drafts.]
    - Adventures of Benny and Watch #2 A Present for Grandfather (Albert Whitman), 1998
      [Fax memo to editor with revisions, rewrite of mss to editor, drafts and note.]